hour,
ninth
At the
cross
Roman
nailed to a
to fill his
unable
and
lungs,
gathered his
Nazareth
Jesus of
and cried out into
strength
dark.
the
God,
"My
my
hast thou forsaken me?"
why
anguish
raw
We hear
forsaken.
man
a
it is that.
And
a
also
But it is
quotation.
had been
words
Those exact
down,
written
person,
in the first
years before
thousand
almost a
morning
that
who died
king
by a
and safe in his
old
bed.
own
God,
"My
my
me?
forsaken
why hast thou
far
why art thou so
me,
helping
from
of
words
and from the
Psalm
my roaring?" This is
twenty-two.
did
Jesus
And the dying
for it by
reach
not
accident.
within
everyone
He was telling
where to look.
exactly
earshot
wrote this song.
David
King
it in the
wrote
He
person I,
first
me,
my
happening
as if it were
body.
to his own
strangeness:
But here is the
near
David himself never came
one
a death like the
describes.
he
is
describes
Because what he
execution.
a public
stripped,
man
A
surrounded,
to death.
mocked
and
worm,
"But I am a
man;
and no
of men,
reproach
a
of the people.
despised
and
they that see me
All
me to scorn:
laugh
out the lip,
shoot
they
the head…" And
shake
they
to what the mockers
listen
say:
actually
LORD
"He trusted on the
him:
deliver
that he would
him,
deliver
let him
in him."
delighted
seeing he
was a soldier and
David
who died of
king
a
age
old
jeering
never stripped before a
crowd,
executed at all.
never
death is he
whose
So
in
describing
voice
own
his
that he
certainty
with such
as a
down
writes it
fact?
the song turns forensic.
Then
like poetry
sounding
It stops
like a
sounding
and starts
statement from a cross
witness
invented
that would not be
centuries.
for
out like
poured
"I am
water,
are
bones
and all my
joint…"
out of
of a man
body
The
up by his arms
hung
pulling apart under
joints
the
weight.
his own
to my
cleaveth
"…my tongue
jaws;
me
brought
and thou hast
the dust of death."
into
thirst
killing
A
cross,
on the
records the
John
the apostle
cry:
thirst.
I
the song says the
Then
business
thing it has no
this early:
knowing
pierced my hands and
"…they
hands and
Pierced
my feet."
feet.
years
thousand
David lived a
turned crucifixion into
Rome
before
science;
a
people never executed
own
his
way.
that
on
reason
There was no
for him to picture
earth
fixed to wood
man
a
and feet
hands
through his
it is,
there
yet
ink,
in
early.
centuries
going,
And it keeps
to the smallest detail:
down
among
garments
"They part my
them,
upon my
lots
and cast
gambling for a
Soldiers
vesture."
clothes.
dead man's
to the foot of
Turn
cross,
the
tells you it
John
and
happened:
be
might
"…that the scripture
fulfilled,
saith,
which
among
raiment
They parted my
them,
they
vesture
and for my
Roman
did cast lots." The
gambling for his clothes
soldiers
a script.
following
were not
one anyway.
fulfilling
They were
Now
objection,
honest
an
a straight
deserves
and it
answer,
pitch.
sales
not a
will say:
reader
A careful
poetry.
this is
who
man
David is a
images dogs,
vivid
reached for
enemies
a lion when his
him.
pressed
word,
one
And on that
pierced,
scholarly
genuine
there is a
dispute:
Hebrew text can
traditional
the
as like a
read
be
at my hands and
lion
than they pierced.
rather
feet
question,
real
That is a
raised.
honestly
cleanly.
So concede it
pierced off the table
Take
entirely,
moment.
just for a
with
left
You are still
stripped and mocked
man
a
death,
to
out of joint,
bones
his
of thirst,
dying
away by
gambled
his clothing
him
killed
the people who
first-person,
written
who suffered
king
by a
of it.
none
disputed word does not
One
that.
carry
does.
convergence
The
itself:
word
And on the
translated
the Greek Old Testament
scholars almost two
Jewish
by
before Jesus was born
centuries
read it they dug,
already
pierced.
or
Christian
This is not a
in after the
smuggled
edit
fact.
was there,
reading
The
hands,
Jewish
in
before there was a
centuries
to defend.
cross
a death
describing
David is
own.
that is not his
us back to
brings
Which
cross,
the
screamed
and to why that
so much.
matters
cry
Jew quoted
first-century
When a
of a
line
the opening
psalm,
reaching for
rarely
he was
line.
just one
way to
natural
The most
it was as a
hear
to the whole song
pointer
the
pulling
the first verse
psalm into the room.
entire
Jesus cried "My
when
So
God,
my
me?"
forsaken
why hast thou
voicing
merely
he was not
pain.
his
himself as
placing
He was
twenty-two.
the I of Psalm
line.
Every
wounded
He was claiming the
as his own,
hands
as
clothes
and the gambled
own
his
below
even as the soldiers
them up,
divided
him
as verse eighteen said
exactly
would.
they
song
He took the whole
himself,
onto
loud,
out
witnesses.
in front of
us:
telling
He was
me.
this one is about
reading
But most people stop
at the cross.
twenty-two
Psalm
there,
stop
And if you
important
you miss the most
it.
about
thing
does not end
song
The
grave.
in a
through,
Halfway
turns
it
violently,
from death to life.
gloriously
that cried
voice
The same
stands up in
suddenly
"forsaken"
worshipping
the middle of a
crowd:
thy name
declare
"I will
brethren:
unto my
of the
midst
in the
will I praise thee."
congregation
man declares nothing.
dead
A
that cried
voice
Yet the
in
alive
"forsaken" now stands
congregation,
the
praising.
that as
read
You could
from the edge
rescue
mere
Jesus
of death except that
onto
song
took this whole
himself,
puts
Testament
and the New
line,
this very
thy name
declare
"I will
my brethren," in the
unto
of the risen Christ.
mouth
man of verse
forsaken
The
worshipper
living
one and the
person,
same
are the
side of
far
on the
did not
God
death because
him in the dust:
leave
hath he hid his
"…neither
from him;
face
unto
cried
but when he
him,
the
then
he heard." And
throws its arms open
song
world:
entire
to the
the ends of the
"All
shall remember and turn
world
LORD:
unto the
of
kindreds
and all the
shall worship before
nations
the
that opens
psalm
thee." The
forsaken man closes
one
with
home.
streaming
with the nations
the
never
The cross was
of the song.
end
hinge.
It was the
last
very
Look at the
David writes.
line
wounds,
After the
turn,
after the
closes on a
song
the
accomplished
something
note of
finished:
work
a
this." A
done
"…he hath
years later,
thousand
cross,
on the
Jesus reaches the
dying
the
note.
same
vinegar,
He receives the
says:
and
finished."
"It is
Done.
this.
done
He hath
ends
two
So hold the
together.
song
of the
The
on the
real
cry was
the
bore
cross he truly
that our sin had
forsaking
earned,
place.
in our
psalm
And yet the same
you how it ends:
tells
did not hide his
God
face,
heard,
he
him up.
raised
he
fell on him
forsaking
The
never
so that it would
on you.
fall
hands were
wounded
And the
enough to reach
wide
spread
of the earth
ends
the
kindred,
every
nation,
far off.
everyone
you.
includes
That
not have to
do
You
before
saving
make yourself worth
come.
you
point
That is the whole
twenty-two:
of Psalm
not with what
ends
it
do,
you must
he hath
what
but with
done
it ends
congregation
and the
room for
has
in still
you.
reaching
The song has been
time.
toward you the whole
the ones
join
Come and
him.
praise
who